Revolutionary Calendar, year 228.
（ナレーター）革命暦228年
スロニムでの戦いのあと―
After the battle of Slonim,
ワルシャワに足止めされた
レイラとアキトたちは―
Leila, Akito and the others were stranded in Warsaw,
where their experiences deepened their bonds of trust.
お互いの信頼を
深め合うこととなった
Meanwhile, riots engulfed Europia
as a result of a cunning scheme
一方 ブリタニアの軍師―
ジュリアス･キングスレイの
奇策によって―
by Britannia 's military advisor,
Julius Kingsley.
ユーロピア全土は騒乱に陥る
Akito and the others leave for
the Ark to prevent a Britannian invasion.
ブリタニアの侵攻を阻止するため
アキトたちは方舟へ向かう
1,000 kilometers south of Saint Petersburg
Euro Britannian Territory
Dnieper Upland
Course is clear.
（オペレーター）
進路 オールクリア
Holy Order of Michael forward operating base
You will be able to reach altitude
of 10, 000 meters in one go.
高度１万メートルまで
一気に上昇できます
（シン･ヒュウガ･シャイング）
フロートシステムか
A Float System, eh?
The homeland isn't to be trifled with, I see.
本国は侮れんな
（オペレーター）
カウントダウン開始
Commencing countdown.
Destination coordinates entry complete.
（ジャン･ロウ）
目的地の座標 入力完了
Auto-nav system activation confirmed.
自動航行システム 起動確認
（アンナ･クレマン）ヒルダ クロエ
Hilda, Chloe, give me a final
check on the Alexander Variants.
アレクサンダ･ヴァリアントの
最終チェックは？
- Everything's okay, Boss!
- They're working perfectly!
（ヒルダ･フェイガン）
ＯＫですよ ボス！
（クロエ･ウィンケル）
バッチリよねー
（サラ･デインズ）打ち上げ８分前
T-minus 8 minutes to liftoff!
Countdown to liftoff has commenced!
打ち上げに向けた
秒読みが開始されました
All systems nominal!
（オリビア･ロウエル）
全システム正常です
（ソフィ･ランドル）
ジョウ･ワイズ！
もしものためよ ＢＲＳの確認
Joe Wise, better safe than sorry.
Confirm BRS.
It looks fine, Dr. Randle.
（ジョウ･ワイズ）
大丈夫です ランドル博士
- Ten. Nine. Eight.
- Make sure you come home safely.
（レイラ･マルカル）
必ず帰ってきて下さい
（クラウス･ウォリック）
さて さてと どうなるか
- Seven. Six. Five.
- Let's keep our fingers crossed...
- Four. Three. Two. One.
（オリビア）全システム準備完了
- All systems ready!
Main engine start!
メインエンジン スタート！
So, that's Apollo's Chariot...
It's beautiful.
あれが“アポロンの馬車”
美しい
（サラ）フェアリング分離30秒前
T-minus 30 seconds to fairing separation.
27.
27 26 25…
26. 25.
Capsule reentry in 10 seconds!
Eight! Seven!
カプセル再突入まで
あと10秒 ８ ７…
Over the North Sea
へへへへ…
俺には分かるんだぜ
I know you're coming...
Akito Hyuga.
ヒュウガ… アキト… ククク…
（サラ）カプセルからの分離成功！
Separation from capsules successful!
All units confirmed!
全機確認！
（クロエ）
アレクサンダ全機 異常なし！
All Alexanders show green!
（日向(ひゅうが)アキト）ん！？
ワイヴァン隊 方舟を捕捉！
Wyvern Squad has detected the Ark!
（オリビア）カウントダウン開始
25 24 23 22 21…
Commencing countdown!
25! 24! 23!
22! 21!
High-altitude observation balloon
has a lock on Wyvern Squad!
（オリビア）高高度観測気球
ワイヴァン隊をロック
ヒュウガ中尉 方舟に到達 え？
Lt. Hyuga has arrived at the Ark!
Does this seem strange to you?
ねぇ これ 変じゃない？
Continuing to close in!
続いて接近！
Ark interior scan data received!
方舟のスキャンデータ
受信しました
あっ！ クレマン大尉！？
Capt. Clement!
データの解析はできたけど…
でも おかしいわね
I've analyzed the data,
- ...but it's strange.
- How so?
（レイラ）どこがですか？
Its mass is too small in relation to its volume.
容積に対して
質量が小さすぎるの
It's almost as if...
これじゃあ まるで
ハリボテの船だわ
It's as if it's hollow.
Wyvern Squad is requesting
weapons authorization!
ワイヴァン隊 火器使用確認！
The Alexanders' power plants
have gone to combat output!
アレクサンダのパワー
戦闘出力！
I was wondering if anyone was home!
（佐山(さやま)リョウ）
やっぱ いやがったか！
There's more than I thought.
思っていた以上にいるな
うっ！
They appear to be engaging the enemy!
（サラ）敵と交戦中と思われます！
Engaging who?
And how many?
敵は？ 敵の規模は？
（サラ）データを解析中です！
Still analyzing data!
Master Ashley...
Good luck to you.
（ヨハネ･ファビウス）
アシュレイ様の ご武運を…
Joannes, I bet you're lonely
over there all by yourself.
ヨハネ…
お前一人じゃ 寂しいだろ？
（シモン･メリクール）
アシュレイ様
- Master Ashley!
（アラン･ネッケル）アシュレイ様
（クザン･モントバン）なぜです！
Why?! Why can 't we go with you?!
（ルネ･ロラン）
なぜ お供できないのですか？
- We'll go with you!
- Master Ashley!
（フランツ･ヴァッロ）
我々も共に！
（ヤン･マーネス）アシュレイ様！
Don 't make me repeat myself!
何度も言わせるな！
俺は一人で行くんだよ！
I'm going alone!
待ってろよ
Just you wait... I'll avenge you.
必ずお前のかたきは
俺がとってやる！
Mark my words!
え！？ これって！？
This is...
司令！
統合本部から緊急通信です！
Commander! Emergency transmission from Joint HQ!
Joint HQ? Who is it from?
統合本部？ 誰からですか？
It's a direct line from Gen. Smilas!
スマイラス将軍から
直接回線です！
Put it on the main screen!
メインスクリーンへ
ご無事でしたか スマイラス将軍
Thank goodness you're safe, Gen. Smilas.
lam, anyway.
（ジィーン･スマイラス）私はな…
But the government and military
are no longer functioning.
しかし 政府も軍も
機能していない
The city of Paris is one big riot.
パリの街は騒乱状態だ
Nevertheless, I will not flee.
だが 私は逃げはしない
General, the cause of the riots, the Ark Fleet,
将軍 今回の騒乱の原因となった
“方舟の船団”は―
is a plot concocted by the
Euro-Britannian Army.
ユーロ･ブリタニア軍が
仕組んだ謀略です
Can you prove that?
証拠はあるのか？
A mission is underway to get
the Wyvern Squad onto the Ark.
（レイラ）今 飛行中の方舟へ―
ワイヴァン隊が
突入作戦を実行中です
We also have confirmation that
they are engaging Britannian Knightmares.
ブリタニア軍ナイトメア隊の
迎撃も確認しています
We must tell the people of
Europia what we have learned!
このことを
ユーロピアの市民に伝えれば…
いまさら事実を伝えても…
Laying out the facts at this
point might not help...
レイラ 人は常に不満を
吐き出すきっかけを待っている
Leila.
People are always looking for
an opportunity to vent their frustrations.
それが人の性だ
It 's human nature.
でも きっと可能性は
まだ残されているはずです
But there must still be a chance!
If it comes from you, it might work.
君なら… 可能かもしれない
人々に届く言葉を
君なら持っているはずだ
You should have the words in
you that will get through to them.
After all, you are the daughter
of Bradow Von Breisgau.
君は あの ブラドー･フォン･
ブライスガウの娘だからだ
If there are Knightmares here,
it means Britannia is behind this!
（香坂(こうさか)アヤノ）
ナイトメアがあるってことは
やっぱりブリタニア！
Ayano!
（リョウ）アヤノ！
チッ！ 逃げ足は速(はえ)ぇな！ うっ！
Damn, they're quick to turn tail, ain't they!
This thing is a...
こいつは！？
Those are drones!
（成瀬(なるせ)ユキヤ）あれはドローンだ
フン 俺たちも
なめられたもんだな！
They must not think much of us!
There's a ton of these things!
Hey! Do you read me?
いっぱい いるよ！
ねぇー！ 聞こえてる！？ うっ！
（アシュレイ）
ククク… やっとかよ
It's about time.
I was getting sick of waiting!
待ちくたびれたぜ～
フン
ハッハハハハ！ 吹き飛んじまえ！
I'll blow you away!
死ねー！
Die!
Akito!
アキトー！
リョウ！
Ryo!
（アシュレイ）ハッハハハハ！
死ね！ 死ねー！
Die! Die!
ん！？ あれは…
That's...
It's that red Knightmare...
I don't believe it!
赤いナイトメア！？ まさか…
シュロッター鋼の装甲！？
Schrötter Steel armor?!
People of Europia, there is
something that I must tell you.
ユーロピアの市民の方々に
お伝えしたいことがあります
Please understand how foolish it is
ブリタニアの情報操作に乗って―
to start rioting in response to
Britannian media manipulation.
騒乱を行うことの愚かしさに
気付いて下さい
We are a unit that fights
Euro-Britannia covertly.
私たちは秘密裏にユーロ･
ブリタニアと戦っている部隊です
つながった
- We're connected!
ユーロピア全域との接続確認
- Link to all of Europia confirmed!
（レイラ）しかも―
What 's more, our soldiers, the ones
fighting on the front lines,
その兵士として 最前線で
闘っているのは―
United Republic of Europia
Paris
are the people we call Elevens
私たちがイレヴンと呼び―
and keep segregated in
internment camps: Japanese.
収容所で隔離している
日本人たちなのです
Out of fear of Britannia, we are
robbing the Japanese of their freedom.
私たちは
ブリタニアに対する恐怖から―
日本人の自由を
奪っているのです
You're not getting away from me! I'll kill you!
逃がしゃしねえ
ブッ殺す！
He's after Akito!
あいつ アキトを！
Yukiya! Ryo! Cover me!
ユキヤ！ リョウ！ 援護して！
Ayano?!
アヤノ！？
It's all yours, Akito!
アキト 頼むぜ
Britannia 's flying weapon does not exist.
（レイラ）ブリタニアの飛行兵器は
存在しません
After controlling the people of
Europia with fear and causing them to riot,
ユーロピアの市民を恐怖で支配し
混乱させたあとに―
軍事侵攻
占領しようとしているのです
they will invade and occupy us militarily.
Normal rounds won't work, huh?
（アキト）通常弾はダメか
Let's try these.
これなら！
死ねよ！
Die, damn it!
チッ！ ふざけんじゃねえ！
Are you kidding me?!
うぜえんだよー！
You're pissing me off!
ふざけろー！
Oh, no you don't!
Why do we hurt one another?
なぜ傷つけ合うのですか？
Are human beings really that sad?
人間とは こんなにも
悲しいものなのでしょうか？
Die...
死ね
Die!
死ね！
We mustn't be ruled by hatred!
憎しみに
支配されてはいけません
地獄へ落ちろ！
Go to hell!
Akito!
アキト！
私たちは
何ものからも自由であるべきです
We should have freedom in all respects.
Die!
死ね
（レイラ）しかし 自由には
責任が伴うのです
However, with freedom comes responsibility.
Die!
死ね！
So that we may live like human beings!
（レイラ）人が人らしくあるために
この世界を
よりよきものにするために
So that we may make this world a better place!
死ね！
Die!
My father, Bradow Von Breisgau, believed that this
それが
ユーロピアの掲げる自由だと―
was the freedom championed by Europia.
私の父 ブラドー･フォン･
ブライスガウは信じていました
Die... Die!
死ね… 死ね！
うっ！ これって？
This is...
まただ！
- It's happening again!
- Die!
（アキト）死ね！
No! Akito!
ダメ！ アキト！
I'm seeing a spike in Akito's brainwave pattern!
（ケイト･ノヴァク）
アキトの脳波動にスパイク発生！
The neuro-devices are out of control!
（フェリッリ･バルトロウ）
ニューロデバイスが
スタンピードします！
The BRS has activated?
ＢＲＳが起動した！？
ジョウ･ワイズ レコードして
Joe Wise! Record it!
（ジョウ）うう…
ランドル博士 間に合いません！
Dr. Randle, there's no time!
Die!
死ね
死ね！
Die!
死神野郎が！
You damn angel of death!
死ね
Die.
死ねー！
Die!
You won't take me!
やられるかよー！
Die.
死ね
Don't do it, Akito!
（アヤノ）ダメ アキト！
ヨハネを…
Joannes...
You killed Joannes!
よくも… ヨハネを！
Kill me, go on!
こ… 殺してみろよ！
ヨハネみたいに殺せよ 死神！
Kill me like you killed Joannes, angel of death!
死ね
Die.
プフォ… ううう… ヨハネ…
Joannes...
アキト
Akito...
（アキト）死ね！
Die.
Die!
（アキト）死ね
（リョウ）ダメだ！ ダメだ アキト
Don 't!
Don 't do it, Akito!
もう これ以上
殺しちゃダメだよ アキト！
There 's been enough killing, Akito!
殺したら 自分を
殺すことになっちゃうよ！
If you kill him, it'll be the same as killing yourself!
Akito! Akito!
（アヤノ）アキト！ アキト！
Akito, live! Live with us!
アキト 生きて！
あたしたちと一緒に生きて！
Now is the time when we must
claim true freedom for ourselves!
今こそ 真の自由を 私たちは
手にしなければ ならないのです！
ハァ ハァ…
I won't give up.
私は諦めません
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
I won't run away.
私は逃げません
（アキト）ハァ… ハァ…
My name is Leila Breisgau.
私の名はレイラ･ブライスガウ
Andlstand with you.
私は皆さんと共にあります
That's the daughter of Assemblyman Breisgau?
（男性）ブライスガウ議員の娘が…
Leila Breisgau!
レイラ･ブライスガウ！
Leila Breisgau! Leila Breisgau!
（市民たち）
レイラ･ブライスガウ！
Leila Breisgau! Leila Breisgau!
Go ahead, shoot. I'm the one
who killed your teammate.
撃てばいい
お前の仲間を殺したのは―
It was me.
俺だ
Crap, I'm out of bullets.
This just isn't my day.
くそっ！ 弾切れだぜ
ツイてねえ！
なあ ヨハネ…
Right, Joannes?
フン まったくよ！
For the love of...
フーン ベタな展開だね
What a corny plot twist.
ちゃかさないの ユキヤ！
- Don't poke fun, Yukiya!
- Fine, whatever...
（ユキヤ）はい はい
All Wyvern Squad beacons have vanished!
ワイヴァン隊全機のビーコンが
消えました！
- What in the world happened?
- Ark status?
一体 何が起こったの！？
（レイラ）方舟は！？
同時に消えました！
今 スキャンし直します！
It disappeared at the same time!
Re-scanning now!
Did the Ark explode?
まさか 方舟が爆発した！？
（レイラ）ああ アキト…
Akito...
Why? Why have we lost their vitals?
どうしてよ どうして
バイタルが消えてるの！？
Everyone's biometrics, they're...
みんなの生命反応が…
Signals from the Alexander aren't coming back online!
アレクたちのシグナル
戻んない
バグよ きっとそうよ
It's a bug. It has to be.
（サラ）
オリビア！ そっちはどう？
Olivia! Any luck?
No. I can't pick up the guide, either.
ダメ！ ガイドも拾えない
It's too soon to give up on the wZERO Unit!
まだ諦めるのは早いぞ！
ｗＺＥＲＯ(ダブルゼロ)部隊を… ん！？
う！？ どうした！？
What is it?!
Units with unknown IFF codes
have breached security perimeter!
（サラ）警戒ラインを突破した
コード不明機がいます
こっちへ向かって来るのか！？
- They're heading our way?
- Yes.
はい！
恐らくブリタニアの…
Most likely Britannian...
クッ！ ナイトメアか
...Knightmares?
Let us go together, Alice.
（マリア･シャイング）
さあ 一緒に参りましょう アリス
（アリス･シャイング）はい…
Yes, Mother.
お母様
He's in an unusual hurry...
いつになく
急いていらっしゃるな
Get up!
立て！
The enemy is here!
Issue orders!
敵が来た 指示を出せ
I...
私は… 私にはできません
I can't...
（クラウス）
クッ！ 甘ったれるな！
Suck it up!
Get on your feet!
（クラウス）早く立て！
あんたには
ここでの役目があるはずだ
You still have your duties here to perform.
You have a responsibility to protect
the lives of the people here.
ここの連中の命は
あんたが守る責任がある
The responsibility that comes with being a commander.
司令官としての責任がな
So protect them.
あんたが守れ
Report enemy position!
敵の位置を報告！
（サラ）は… はい！
Yes, ma'am!
Leila...
レイラ…
Enemy is to the northeast!
Distance, 25km!
敵の位置 北東 距離25！
時速140キロで
近づいてきます！
Closing in at a speed of 140kph!
140キロ！？ 森の中を！？
140kph? Through a forest?!
Your thoughts, Capt. Clement?
クレマン大尉の考察は？
If it's a four-legged Knightmare
that can gallop like an animal,
動物のような四脚疾走ができる
ナイトメアなら―
悪路でもスピードを出せるわ
it could run at speed on rough terrain.
A four-legged Knightmare?
四脚のナイトメア？ ハッ！
（アキト）兄さん…
Brother...
The minefield... Activate the
minefield to the southeast.
地雷原… 南東の地雷原…
No, activate all defense systems!
いいえ 全防御システム起動！
敵の侵入を全力で阻止する！
Use everything we have
to halt their approach!
They detected us already, eh?
もう見つけたか
They seem smarter than
Europia's main force fools.
ふぬけのユーロピア本隊とは
違うようだ
These will be worth crushing.
潰しがいがある
（サラ）敵機 速度 落ちません！
- Enemy speed is not decreasing!
- Approaching minefield!
（オリビア）地雷原に接近！
Minefield reaction confirmed!
地雷原 反応確認！
（サラ）
敵機！ 移動速度 落ちません！
Enemy rate of movement is not slowing!
It's running faster than the mines can detonate?!
地雷が爆発するより速く
走っているのかよ
Enemy is changing course!
敵機 コース変更
12度 東にずれてきています
It's shifting 12 degrees eastward!
Lord Hyuga! You've gone out too far ahead!
ヒュウガ様
先行しすぎておられます！
ヒュウガ様！
Lord Hyuga!
（シン）ジャン 援護射撃 座標…
Jean, support fire.
These coordinates.
Commencing support fire!
援護射撃 開始します！
Area around front gate hit!
System Sigma-3 is down!
正門周辺に着弾！
システムシグマ３ ダウン！
Defensive wall activation in 90 seconds!
防御壁起動まで あと90！
（シン）フン
Lord Hyuga!
（ジャン）ヒュウガ様！？
Lord Hyuga, are you all right?
ヒュウガ様？ ご無事ですか！？
Lord Hyuga!
ヒュウガ様！
A wall has sprouted around the castle.
城の周りに壁が出現した
調べろ
Scout it.
ハァ…
Right away, Lord Hyuga!
はい ヒュウガ様！
この城の司令官…
思ったより手応えがありそうだ
The commander of this castle
appears to be more formidable
than I thought.
（オリビア）
防御壁 展開完了確認！
Defensive wall deployment completion confirmed!
We have visuals of enemy Knightmare!
（サラ）
敵ナイトメアの映像が出ます！
ヘッ この壁は そう簡単には
乗り越えられないぜ
You'll have to
try harder than that to get over that wall.
Remain at highest state of alert. 24-hour standby.
このまま最上級警戒
24時間待機
Also,
あと ワイヴァン隊への
コールは続行
keep hailing Wyvern Squad.
了解
Roger.
Commander, don't you think
you should get a little rest?
司令 少しお休みになったほうが
よかないですか？
I'm not--
私はまだ…
I'll handle things here.
ここは俺が やっときます
今しか休める時はないですよ
This will be your only chance to get any rest.
ウォリック中佐…
Lt. Col. Warwick...
サラちゃ～ん おじさんと
２人で居残り よろしく～
Sara?
- You and I will be staying here!
- Yes, sir!
（サラ）はい！
The rest of you, take a quick break!
（クラウス）
あとは みんなも一時休息！
さあ 司令
Go on, Commander.
よろしくお願いします
ウォリック中佐
Keep an eye on things here,
Lt. Col. Warwick.
（オスカー）中佐…
（クラウス）ん？
Lt. Colonel.
アキトたちは
帰還できると思いますか？
Do you think Akito and the others
will manage to make it back?
あいつらが そう簡単に
死ぬわけねえよ
Come on, those guys would
never die that easily.
（シン）騎士団が到着次第
総攻撃を開始する
As soon as the Order arrives,
we will launch a full-scale assault.
ジャン お前に指揮は任せる
Jean, I'll leave command of the operation to you.
Yes, Lord!
Akito...
（シン）アキト…
Are you still alive?
まだ生きているか？
（エリザベート）ニャー
ニャー
エリザ…
Eliza...
（エリザベート）ニャー
Akito, he...
アキトが…
アキト…
Akito...
（エリザベート）ニャー
Sorry about this, Sara. You and Olivia
are the only actual military personnel.
（クラウス）
悪いな サラちゃん
あんたとオリビアちゃんだけが
軍属なんでな
It's fine. I've been trained to handle long-duration missions.
平気です 長時間作戦行動の
訓練も受けてますから
そうかい
You have, huh?
Still, I'd rather not
でも この城を
戦場には したくないよなあ
have this castle turned into a battlefield.
Suzaku...
（ジュリアス･キングスレイ）
スザク…
Say, Suzaku...
ねぇ スザク
It's hot again today, don't you think?
今日も暑いね
Look, Suzaku.
ねぇ スザク…
Look at the sunflower.
Isn't it pretty?
ほら ひまわりが きれいだね
スザク
Suzaku, isn't it pretty?
きれいだね
The Order of Michael's Black, Blue,
and White Regiments have arrived.
（騎士）ミカエル騎士団
黒の団 青の団 白の団―
到着しました
Have all troops take up their assigned positions.
各隊は作戦通り布陣
24時間戦闘待機
Remain on 24-hour combat alert.
Tell them not to forget that this is enemy territory.
ここは敵地であることを
忘れるなと伝えろ
Yes, Lord!
（市民たち）
レイラ･ブライスガウ！
Leila Breisgau! Leila Breisgau!
United Republic of Europia
Paris
Leila Breisgau!
レイラ･ブライスガウ！
Leila Breisgau! Leila Breisgau!
（男性）
ブライスガウに会わせてくれよ
Let us see Breisgau!
（男性）我々のレイラー！
Show us our Leila!
Soldier, take these flowers!
（女性）兵隊さん この花を
Give these flowers to Leila Breisgau!
この花をレイラ･ブライスガウに
お渡し下さい
Please stand by for
an emergency broadcast.
（男性）これより
緊急放送が始まります
Élysée Palace, Presidential Office
The provisional government
has an important message
市民の皆様に―
臨時政府より
重要なお知らせがあります
for you, the citizens.
Citizens of Europia, there is sad
news that I must report to you.
ユーロピアの市民に―
私は悲しい知らせを
伝えなければならない
The woman who kindled the fires
of courage and hope within us all,
我々に… 勇気と希望の火を
ともしてくれた―
レイラ･ブライスガウが死んだ
Leila Breisgau, is dead.
Leila Breisgau...
レイラ･ブライスガウが…―
... is dead.
死んだ
Leila Breisgau is dead.
レイラ･ブライスガウが死んだ！
We have confirmed reports that Weiswolf Castle Base,
レイラ･ブライスガウがいた
ヴァイスボルフ城基地が―
where Leila Breisgau was stationed,
ユーロ･ブリタニアの
奇襲に遭い―
came under Euro-Britannian
attack and was destroyed.
全滅したことが確認された
Even though Weiswolf Castle is
located some 1000km away
ヴァイスボルフ城は―
ユーロ･ブリタニアとの
国境から―
from our border with Euro-Britannia,
1,000キロ以上も
離れた場所であったが―
our enemy crossed the border and attacked it.
敵は国境線を越えて
襲ってきた
I shall continue what
Leila Breisgau started.
私は レイラ･ブライスガウの
想いを引き継ぐ
Euro-Britannia killed our Leila,
レイラを殺した
ユーロ･ブリタニアを―
and I will make them pay.
私は許さない！
For untold years, our ancestors
were exploited by royals and nobility.
我々の先祖たちは 長きにわたり
王侯貴族たちに搾取されてきた
そして革命によって
その矛盾を正したのだ
And they righted that injustice
by means of the Revolution.
Much blood was spilled in the
Revolution, and those who spilled it
革命で多くの血が流れ―
その流した血は
より多くの血を求めた
called for still more.
They tried to avenge a millennium of grudges
1,000年にわたる恨みを―
by killing royals, killing nobles,
killing all they could.
王や貴族を殺し
殺し尽くすことで晴らそうとした
だが 新大陸へ逃れた
王や貴族の末裔たちは―
But the descendants of the kings and
nobles who escaped to the New World
have been waiting for the
right time to take their revenge!
復讐の時を待っていた！
Looks like Gen. Smilas' regime
has assumed full control of Europia.
ユーロピアはスマイラス将軍の
軍事政権が完全に掌握したようです
The descendants of those fiends
（スマイラス）
悪しき者たちの末裔は
革命によって追われた土地を―
will attack us to reclaim the
lands they were driven from
再び取り戻すため
襲い来るのだ！
by the Revolution!
The General's cut a deal with Britannia...
将軍は ブリタニアと
取り引きしたんだよ
Do you have proof of that?
証拠があるのでしょうか？
俺が ここの情報を
ブリタニアに売った
I sold intel on this place to Britannia.
If the General really did care for you,
（クラウス）将軍が 本当に
司令のためを想っているのなら―
俺なんかを
副司令にはしないでしょうよ
he wouldn't have made me
your second in command.
お嬢さんの医療費のためですね
You did it to pay for your
daughter's medical bills, didn't you?
そこまで知ってて
俺を泳がしていたんですか？
You knew everything, but
you left me at large?
People can change.
人は変われます
They never change!
Once scum, always scum!
変われはしない！
クズはクズのままだ！
Just hand over the castle
and the secret weapon.
この城も秘密兵器も
みんな渡しちまいな
それが
ユーロ･ブリタニアの望みだ
That's what Euro-Britannia wants.
それしか あんたたちが
生き残る方法はない
That's the only way you guys
are getting out of this alive.
If Euro-Britannia gets their
hands on the ultra-long range transport,
超長距離輸送機を―
ユーロ･ブリタニアが
手に入れれば―
war will spread to every corner of the globe.
世界が戦火に
包まれてしまいます
You risking your neck to fight
here isn't gonna change anything.
あんた一人が命がけで戦っても
何も変わらないよ
The world's not that nice a place.
世界はそんなに優しくない
私は…
- I'll--
- Listen!
あんたは あんた自身と
ここの連中の命を―
Just worry about saving your
life and the lives of the people here!
助けることだけを
考えていればいいんだ！
それだけで十分だ
That's more than enough!
Nobody could fault you for that!
責める資格があるやつなんて
誰もいない
（スマイラス）自由のために
命を捨てることをためらうな
Do not hesitate to lay down
your lives in the name of freedom!
Even if your life is extinguished,
the light of your resolve will shine on!
命尽きても その志は永遠に残る
命を惜しみ 奴隷になるのか？
Will you cling to your lives and be slaves?!
私は断固 戦う 自由のために！
lam determined to fight!
For freedom!
Rabble-rousers like him are
never the ones who die.
ああやって たきつけるやつらは
絶対に死なない
足元に屍を築き
それを踏み台にして―
They pile up corpses underfoot
and use them as a steppingstone
to reach the high fruit they're after.
高き所の果実をつかみ取る
My fellow citizens! Rise up!
市民たちよ 立ち上がれ！
ブライスガウが守ろうとした
明日のために戦え！
For the tomorrow that
Breisgau tried to protect, fight!
（市民たち）ワアアー！
将軍はユーロピアの皇帝に
なろうとしてるんだよ
The General's trying to make
himself emperor of Europia.
You were just a means to that end.
あんたは利用されただけだ
（エリザベート）ニャー
（クラウス）
俺がユーロ･ブリタニアとの
交渉の手引きをする
I'm going to set up negotiations with Euro-Britannia.
Please draw up a letter of surrender.
司令は降伏文書の作成を
お願いします
We would like to see Lord Shaing.
（ブロンデッロ）シャイング卿に
お目通り願いたい！
If there is an issue,
I shall see to it.
（ジャン）ご用件なら私が承ります
総帥は今 ユーロ･ブリタニアの
政もなさらねばならぬ多忙ゆえ
The Grand Master is now
forced to busy himself with
Euro-Britannian government affairs.
（ドレ）貴様に言われるまでもない
承知している！
You don't have to tell us that.
We're perfectly aware.
That is just it.
（ショルツ）だからこそだ
We wish to ask him
この辺境の基地を
なぜ 越境までして―
why we must cross the border to
take this castle in the middle of nowhere!
落とす必要があるのか聞きたい
If you do not know why,
理由を知らねば…
will you be afraid to fight?
戦いに臆しますか？
グッ！ 我らミカエルの三剣豪を
愚弄するか！
You dare insult the Three
Swordmasters of Michael?
Is it not poor form for a
knight to draw his sword lightly?
騎士が剣を安易に抜くのは
不作法ではありませんか？
Is this what Lord Manfredi taught you?
それがマンフレディ卿の
教えですか？
貴様っ！
- Why, you little--
- Enough, Scholtz!
やめろ ショルツ！
我らが主 マンフレディ卿を
揶揄することは許さんぞ！
We won't allow anyone to
mock our master, Lord Manfredi!
マンフレディ卿は
お亡くなりになられた
Lord Manfredi is dead.
しかも
ミカエル騎士団の総帥を―
In addition, his will bequeathed
シャイング卿に引き継ぐとの
遺言状も残しておられる
the title of Grand Master of the Holy
Order of Michael to Lord Shaing.
In which case,
（ジャン）…であるからには―
you are honor-bound as knights
to obey Lord Shaing's orders.
シャイング卿のご指示には
従うが騎士道
Prove on the field of battle that
the reputation of the Three Swordmasters
戦場の働きで 三剣豪の名が
偽りでないことを お示しなさい
is not a lie.
When will the battle be, then?!
ならば戦いは いつになる！？
（ジャン）フッ それはまだ
お教えできません
I cannot tell you that just yet.
しかし 三剣豪の皆様なら
いつであろうが―
But I'm sure that the
Three Swordmasters
will be ready and waiting
when the battle finally comes.
戦いの準備に
抜かりはないかと思いますが
（シンの母）シン…
Shin...
シン…
My most beloved child.
私の最愛の子
Shin!
シン…
My Shin...
私のシン
あなたには お父様のように
なってほしくはなかった
I didn't want you to turn
out as your father did.
母さんを許して…
Forgive me!
消えろ
Away with you. I thought I told you
that a woman like you is no mother of mine.
お前のような女
母ではないと言ったはずだ
（シンの母）
そう… だからアキトを…
I know, so please protect Akito.
父を裏切ってか？
By betraying Father?
Akito 's father was kind to me.
アキトの父親は私に優しかった
でも あなたの
お父様に殺された…
But he was killed by your father.
Oh, he was killed...
ああ… 殺されたのよ
そして 私は
あなたに殺された
And then I was killed by you...
Me, the woman who gave birth to you!
あなたを産んだ私を
あなたは…
Begone, ghost!
消えろよ 亡霊！
（シンの母）キャアアアー
（ミケーレ･マンフレディ）
シン 我が弟よ
Shin... My younger brother.
Shin Hyuga.
ヒュウガ･シン
Lord Manfredi.
マンフレディ卿…
Hurry to my side, Shin.
（マンフレディ）
早く我が元へ シン
早くお前に会いたい
I wish to be reunited with you soon.
もうすぐです
もうすぐ あなたと会えます
It won't be long. Soon,
I can join you, Manfredi.
マンフレディ
（マリア）私もお待ちしております
I am also waiting.
義理の母ではありますが
あなたを愛しています
I may only be your foster mother,
but I love you all the same.
And I you, Maria. I wish to be reunited with you soon
私もです マリア
あなたにも早く会いたい…
（アリス）お兄様
Brother...
I miss you, too.
私も会いたいの
It 's so very cold here...
Hurry.
ここは寒いの
早く 早く私たちの元に
いらっしゃって下さい お兄様
Please hurry and join us, Brother.
If I can...
会えるのなら…
I love you.
愛している…
Lord Hyuga!
（ジャン）ヒュウガ様！
おやめ下さい… ヒュウガ様！
Please stop that, Lord Hyuga!
Ghosts were speaking to me.
亡霊の声を聞いた
（シン）
いや 亡霊などいるはずがない
No, surely there can be no such thing as ghosts.
This world is not so wonderful
that the dead would cling to it.
死人が執着するほど―
この世界は
すばらしくはないからな
ハッハハハ…
私はヒュウガ様となら
地獄へでも お供いたします
If it let me be with you, I would
follow you into the gates of Hell.
Please stand back a bit!
（オスカー）少し離れて下さい
（アンナ）レイラ 気をつけて
Leila, be careful.
（レイラ）
フッ 心配しないで アンナ
Don't worry, Anna.
Prep the Alexanders so they
are ready to be disarmed.
アレクサンダたちの
武装解除の準備をしておいて下さい
停戦交渉が終了したら
すぐにお願いします
As soon as the cease-fire
negotiations are over, do it immediately.
If you go with the Commander,
中佐が司令と共に行けば
もしもの時―
who will be in charge of Weiswolf
Castle if something goes wrong?
誰がヴァイスボルフ城の
指揮をするのです？
そん時はハメル少佐が
やればいいよ
If it comes to that, you do it, Maj. Hammel.
I'm not qualified!
（オスカー）そんな 私には…
I don't think it'll come to that, though.
（クラウス）まあ そんなことには
ならないと思うけどな
Keep an eye on things.
あとはよろしく～
It's gotten colder. I hope this snow doesn't stick.
冷えてきたなあ
積もんなきゃいいけど
You're the Schwarzwald Mole?
お前が
シュバルツバルトのモグラ？
Yeah. This is the draft of the
Commander's surrender document.
ああ 司令官の降伏文書案だ
Our only condition is that you allow
all base personnel to leave unharmed.
こちらの条件は 基地内の人間を
全員 無傷で撤退させたいだけだ
Where is the base's decryption cypher?
（ジャン）
基地の暗号解読用のコードは？
（クラウス）
フッ そっちがそれをお望みなら…
It's in there if you want to have it.
（ジャン）“アポロンの馬車”の
データもあるのだな？
I assume this also contains data on Apollo's Chariot?
Yeah.
（ジャン）スパイのお前が
望むのであれば―
Since you were our spy,
I could arrange for asylum in Euro-Britannia if you wish.
ユーロ･ブリタニアへの
亡命も手配するが…
True... I might take you up on that.
そうだな
フッ それもいいかもな
Ancient Roman ruins...
（シン）古代ローマの遺跡とは
あなたは趣味がいい マルカル中佐
You have excellent taste,
Lt. Col. Malcal.
（レイラ）私の要求を
受けて頂けるのでしょうか？
Do you find my terms acceptable?
There is no need to rush.
We have time.
（シン）急ぐことはないでしょう
時間はある
To think that a girl like you planned
the Ghost of Hannibal operations...
あなたのような女性が―
“ハンニバルの亡霊”の作戦を
考えられたとは 驚きですよ
It's quite a surprise.
我々ユーロ･ブリタニアは
そのために多くの損害を受けた
We Euro-Britannians suffered
heavy losses as a result.
No, please don't misunderstand.
（シン）
いや 勘違いしないでほしい
I have no desire for revenge against you.
私は あなたに
復讐したいわけではない
On the contrary,
I wish to thank you.
むしろ あなたに感謝したい
感謝？
Thank me?
The foolish Euro-Britannian
nobles refuse to let go of that
（シン）騎士道などという
中世の遺物を捨てない―
愚かなユーロ･ブリタニアの
貴族どもに―
chivalry nonsense that's a relic of the Middle Ages.
You struck fear into their hearts.
恐怖を与えた
ハァ… 愉快だったよ
It was most entertaining.
Plus, Euro-Britannia fell into
my hands even sooner
それに私の計画より早く―
ユーロ･ブリタニアを
手に入れることとなった
than I had planned.
Lord Shaing, this is the
second time we have met.
シャイング卿
あなたに会うのは２度目です
I see. You were in that
Knightmare in that battle, were you?
そうか… あの時のナイトメアは
あなただったか
Lt. Hyuga... Akito called you his bro--
ヒュウガ中尉は…
アキトは あなたを兄と…
アキトは死んだよ
Akito is dead.
I have no need for a brother who
would disobey his brother's orders.
兄の命令に背いた弟を
私は必要としない
アキトは生きています
Akito is alive.
（シン）ん？ お前に何が分かる？
What do you know about it?
Akito promised me that he would return.
（レイラ）アキトは帰ってくると
約束してくれました
ほう…
アキトは あなたのことを
とても心配していました
Akito was very worried about you.
He said he wanted to stop you.
あなたを止めたいと…
だから？
What of it?
アキトは帰ってきます
Akito will come back.
I believe in him.
私は信じています！
How revolting.
不愉快だ
お前のような愚かしいやつを見ると
吐き気がする
When I look at a simpleton
like you, it makes me want to vomit.
信じる？
You believe in him?
お前は まだ分からないのか？
You still do not understand?
That you have been betrayed?
裏切られたことも
スマイラス将軍のことを？
You're referring to Gen. Smilas?
Allow me to edify you.
（シン）
教えてやる 人を信じるとは―
Belief in others is an illusion
concocted by the clever
バカどもを利用するために
さかしい者たちが作った幻影だ
to exploit the stupid.
人間が信じるに値すると
本気で思ってるのか？
Do you honestly feel that
humans are worth believing in?
信じれば きっと
その想いは伝わります
If you believe in others, they're sure to reciprocate.
That is why you are betrayed and exploited!
だから！
お前は裏切られ 利用される！
（シン）人間にそんなものなど
みじんもないということを―
You need to learn that humanity
isn't the least bit worth believing in.
お前は思い知るがいい
With people, it's every man for himself.
人は みんな
自分さえよければいい
If you have plenty, to hell with others.
自分だけが豊かであればいい
いや それだけじゃない
No, it goes beyond that.
The more miserable others are,
他人が不幸であればあるほど―
the more convinced they are
that they themselves are happy.
自分の幸せを
確認できるとさえ思っている―
What contemptible creatures they are.
あさましい生き物だ
かわいそうですね
That is so sad.
何が？
What is?
あなたがです！
You are!
Don't move!
動くな！
You're hopeless, I see.
Then believe what you will.
救いがたいな
なら信じればいい
You will be gone from this
world before he returns.
その前に お前は
この世界から消える フッ
Die!
死ね！
グッ… うわっ 何だ？ クッ…
What was that?!
（ジャン）
クッ… ヒュウガ様っ！
Lord Hyuga!
（シン）ハァ ハァ…
Are you all right, Lord Hyuga?
（ジャン）
大丈夫ですか？ ヒュウガ様
Yes...
（クラウス）クッ あんたは何を？
What did you do?
Lord Shaing, what do you hope
to attack using Apollo's Chariot?
シャイング卿 あなたは
“アポロンの馬車”で―
どこを攻撃しようとして
おられるのですか？
Pendragon.
ペンドラゴン
ハッ！ ブリタニアの首都の
ペンドラゴン？
Pendragon, the capital of Britannia?
（シン）そうだ
That's right.
皇帝を殺すつもりか？
You're planning to kill the emperor?
今 皇帝が死ねば
ブリタニアは…！
If the emperor died now,
Britannia will...
No, not just Britannia. The resulting
chaos would engulf the entire world
いや それどころか
世界がその混乱に巻き込まれ―
and huge wars would break
out around the planet!
世界中で大戦が始まるぞ
それが望みだ
That's precisely what I want. I want
the world to be buried in corpses.
この地上が屍で
埋め尽くされればいい
You're insane...
狂ってるぞ… お前
（シン）降伏など認めない
I do not accept your surrender.
We will conquer that castle
あの城を攻め滅ぼし
一人残らず殺す
and kill everyone in it!
Anything I require,
I will take by force!
必要なものは
俺がこの手で奪う
ジャン その２人を殺せ
Jean. Kill those two.
司令… 申し訳ない
Commander, I'm sorry.
あなただけでも
投降して下さい
Surrender by yourself!
ヘッ さすがの俺でも―
Not even a guy like me could
do something that shameful.
そこまで恥知らずなことは
できませんよ
Stand back.
離れて
何だか やばいな…
Things look dicey down there.
こいつらを殺せ！
Kill them all.
うっ！？ でもヒュウガ様
彼らには まだ利用価値が
But Lord Hyuga, we can still
use them if they're alive!
- Shoot them dead!
- Yes, sir!
（シン）撃ち殺せっ！
諦めが悪いな
You don't know when to give up, do you?
ヒュウガ様！
Lord Hyuga...
ハッ！？
（クラウス）伏せろ！
Take cover!
Am I crazy, or was that
an explosion shockwave?
ねぇ 爆発の衝撃波だよね？
Yeah, I think it must have been.
（オリビア）
うん 間違いないと思う
あっ！
なんか通信が入ってきてるよ！
I'm receiving some kind of transmission!
The Alexander beacons are back online?
アレクサンダのビーコンが
復活した！
Whose Alexander?
誰のアレクサンダ？
Synchronized!
（サラ）同期した！
Guys! Do you read me?
（ユキヤ）みんな 聞こえてる？
Wyvern Squad here!
If you read me, respond!
（ユキヤ）こちらワイヴァン隊
聞こえてたら応えてよ
え！？ ユキヤ君！
Yukiya!
Hey, Sara! Long time, no hear!
You 're sounding well.
（ユキヤ）やあ サラ 久しぶり！
元気そうだね
（レイラ）ううっ…
（クラウス）うっく…
What was that?
あれは？
From overhead, huh?
上空からか
Lord Hyuga?
ヒュウガ様
アキトか…
Akito, eh?
He's alive...
生きていた
Did you see a flash of light just now?
（アンナ）今 何か
光が見えませんでしたか？
Yes, I'm sure of it.
（オスカー）ええ 確かに…
What do you suppose it was?
何の光だろう？
An Alexander!
（アンナ）アレクサンダ！
あぁ！ アキトー！
Akito!
（オスカー）え？ アキト？
アキトなんですか！？
Akito? It's Akito?!
But how?!
（サラ）でも どうして？
何で今まで
通信してこなかったのよ！
Why didn't you radio us before now?!
Sorry! "To deceive one 's enemies,
begin with one 's allies "and all that.
（ユキヤ）ごめん 敵をだますには
まず味方からってね
- That's mean!
- We were worried sick!
ひどいよ！
心配させて！
They're... They're all alive.
What a relief!
みんな… みんな生きてる
よかった～
はいはい よかったね ジョウ
- It sure is, Joe.
- Don't cry, Joe!
泣かないで ジョウ
What wonderful news, Leila.
よかったわね レイラ
見えたぞ！ アキト！
I see it, Akito!
Brother...
兄さん…
Akito!
アキト…
（アヤノ）ねぇ
何であいつを信用するの？
Tell me, why are we trusting that guy?
That Ashley guy, I mean.
アシュレイとかってやつをさっ！
Jealousy is an ugly thing, Ayano.
（ユキヤ）
アヤノ よくないよ 嫉妬は
誰が誰に
嫉妬なんかしてるのよ！？
Who 's being jealous of who?!
You're an open book, Ayano.
アヤノは
分かりやすすぎるんだよな
If you don 't control your emotions better,
もうちょっと感情を抑えないと
恋の駆け引きはできないよ
you 'll never be able to play the game of love.
I never imagined the day would come
ユキヤに
そんなこと言われるなんて―
想像もしなかったなぁ
when I'd hear those words from you!
アヤノ 時間だ 降りるぞ
Ayano, it 's time.
Let's bail.
あっ！？ ユキヤ
帰ったらじっくり話そうな
Yukiya, when we get back, we're
gonna have a nice, long chat!
Yeah, yeah...
はい はい
We 'll be waiting for you on the ground, Yukiya!
（リョウ）ユキヤ じゃあ
下で待ってるからな！
Roger that. I'll bail out as
planned, so I'll see you later.
了解 予定通りに降りるから
またあとで
（アヤノ）ユキヤ
Yukiya.
早く来いよ！
Don 't keep us waiting.
（シン）どうだ ジャン
私の言った通りだろ
Well, Jean?
Isn't it exactly as I said?
Oh, crap! It's a Knightmare!
やべぇ ナイトメアじゃねえか！
Commander!
司令！
ヴェルキンゲトリクスだ！
アキト！
It's the Vercingetorix!
Akito!
司令！
Commander?
アキト…
Akito...
（アシュレイ）シャイング卿！
Lord Shaing!
You've got some nerve,
てめえー よくも俺がいるのに
方舟を爆破させやがったなー！
blowing the Ark while I was still on it!
うわっ あぶあぶ
ジャン 危ねえだろが！
Jean! Watch it!
Shut your mouth, traitor!
I'll kill you myself!
黙れ 裏切り者！
この私が殺してやる！
ふざけんな！
裏切ったのは そっちだろうが！？
Get real! You're the traitor!
Who the hell is that?
誰だ あいつ！？
Lt. Col, get to the boat!
中佐は先にボートへ！
え？ ちょっ？
ちょっと待ちなって うっ！？
Hey, wait a damn minute!
おっさん！ アキトに頼まれた！
Pops! Akito sent me!
さっさと逃げるぞ！
Let's get out of here!
（クラウス）ああ う…
だ だ… 誰だよ お前？
Who are you?
You haven 't changed one bit since then.
（シン）お前は あのころと
何も変わらない
You 're still a child.
幼子のままだ
You have no idea how the world works.
世の中を理解していない
（アキト）兄さんは間違っている
You're wrong, Brother.
戦いでは何も変えられない
Fighting can't change anything.
この世界の愚かな支配者どもに
従う者たちを―
I can't allow the people of
the world to go on following
このままに
しておくことはできない
the same foolish rulers.
アキト 弟なら
お前にも分かるはずだ
Akito,
if you are my little brother, you ought to understand
what I am trying to do.
私の想いが…
Brother...
兄さん…
Akito!
アキト！
司令？
Commander?
Don't do it, Akito!
You're not like him!
ダメ アキト あなたは違う！
チッ アキト その女を殺せ！
Akito, kill that woman!
お前に命令できるのは
俺だけだ
No one can give you orders but me.
Kill her!
（シン）殺せ！
殺せ
Kill her!
（アキト）司令…
Commander.
アキト？
Akito!
I'm getting us out of here.
逃げます
しっかり
つかまっていて下さい！
Hang on tight.
Lt. Col. Warwick!
ウォリック中佐！
アキトー！ 飛び乗れ！
Akito, jump on!
Commander, hold on.
司令 つかまっていて下さい
I'm going to jump.
飛びます
Ano hi watashi tachiga mita yume wo
Do you still remember
kimi wa mada obo ete imasuka?
the dream we had that day?
Tsumetai kaze no naka de
As a cold wind blew,
tori tachi ga tobi satta sora ni
birds took flight into the sky,
hitosuji no kumo ga ko wo ega ite
where a line of clouds traced an arc
おっさん 飛ばせよ！
Pops! Punch it!
Sure, but it's a little cold to be out for a cruise...
higashi e doko mademo nobite yuku.
that stretched endlessly to the east.
クルージングには
ちょい寒いけどな
Hageshi ku ikizu tomo tsuyo ku
Please never let me go.
司令がアレクサンダに！？
The Commander and an Alexander?!
Anata aishita katta.
I wanted to love you
deeply without living like blazes.
しゃあー！！
Yes!
Sono te wo tada
I simply wanted
レイラ！ レイラー！
Leila! Leila!
tada shizuka ni mamoru you ni
to go on grasping your hand in silence
nigitte itakatta. (Please never let me go).
as if to protect you. (Please never let me go).
Sayounara utsuku shii hito yo.
Farewell, you beautiful person.
Anata to iu ashita wa
The tomorrow that is you
don na toki mo kibou eto kawaru hikari wo
brought with it a light
tsurete kima sita.
that always transformed into hope.
Mizu wa nagare uruoshite yuku.
Water flows, nourishing all,
Soshite kono hoshi wa kyou mo aoi mama de.
and this world remains green again today.
（ユキヤ）しょうがないよね
これ 戦争だから…
I hate to do this, but it's war...
Sorry, but I have teammates to protect.
（ユキヤ）ごめんね 僕は
仲間を守らなきゃいけないんだ
- Company 2's been wiped out!
- All squads, report in!
（ブロンデッロ）
報告しろ！ 各隊報告！
落ち着け！
Calm yourselves!
- A second one is coming!
- Lord Shaing...
うっ！？ シャイング卿！？
（シン）
敵は雲の上だ 座標を伝える
The enemy is above the clouds.
I'm sending you the coordinates.
Shoot it down with a Canterbury.
カンタベリーで撃墜しろ
ユキヤ！
Yukiya!
ユキヤ…
Yukiya...
ああ… ユキヤー！
Yukiya!
Akito.
（シン）アキト…
お前の愛する者たちを―
I'm going to kill
皆殺しにしてやるよ
everyone that you love.
お前の目の前でね
Right in front of you.
EPISODE 4
Memories of Hatred
FINAL EPISODE
To Beloved Ones